Finding Aid for the Morton Feldman Papers, 1950-1999
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library
- Oversize, circa 1955-1994, XI.; 1 box
  - 1 Box of 22 slides, chiefly of pages from Feldman's scores (Box 16, Item 12)
Boucher, Jeff W. and H. McCoy Jones. Rugs of the Yomud Tribes. Christmas exhibition of the International Hajji Baba Society, Inc., held at the Cosmos Club, Washington, D.C.
Ettinghausen, Richard, et al. Prayer Rugs. Catalogue of an exhibition held at the Textile Museum, Sept. 21-Dec. 28, 1974 and at the Montclair N.J. Art Museum, Jan. 20-Mar. 16, 1975.
NK2809.I8 P73
Islamic Carpets from the Joseph V. McMullen Collection. Catalogue of an exhibition held at the Hayward Gallery, London, 19 October-10 December 1972.
Kaukasische Teppiche. Museum für Kunsthandwerk, Frankfurt Nov. 17-Dec. 16, 1962.
Mackie, Louise W. The Splendor of Turkish Weaving: An Exhibition of Silks and Carpets of the 13th - 18th Centuries. Catalog of exhibition held at the Textile Museum, Washington, D.C. November 9, 1973 through March 24, 1974.
NK2865.A1 M3
The Qashqa-'I of Iran: World of Islam Festival 1976. Catalogue of an exhibition held 24 April to 29 May at the Whitworth Art Gallery and at seven other museums until autumn 1977.
Yohe, Ralph S. and H. McCoy Jones, eds. Turkish Rugs. Catalog of an exhibition sponsored by The Washington Hajji Baba (The Rug Society of Washington D.C., Inc.) in cooperation with The Textile Museum May 26 - September 21, 1968.
NK2865 .A1 W36
Carpet auction catalogs
Bolton Gallery
November 3 1983
J.P.J. Homer Oriental Rugs
May 17 - June 8
Lefevre & Partners, London, England
April 27, 1979
October 5, 1979
November 30, 1979
December 9, 1979
February 15, 1980
April 25, 1980
May 23, 1980
July 4, 1980
October 31, 1980
November 22, 1980
February 20, 1981
April 15, 1981
July 17, 1981
October 16, 1981
November 27, 1981
February 26, 1982
April 23, 1982
June 18, 1982
November 26, 1982
March 4, 1983
April 22, 1983
June 17, 1983
July 15, 1983
October 21, 1983
November 25, 1983
February 17, 1984
April 6, 1984
May 25, 1984
November 23, 1984
March 8, 1985
June 14, 1985
PB Eighty-Four
June 13, 1979
Aug. 16 (Sale 641)
PB Eighty-Four, NY
October 17, 1979
Phillips, Son & Neale
June 24, 1986
September 30, 1986
December 8, 1987
Phillips, NY
May 30, 1986
February 24, 1987
October 20, 1987
April 12, 1988
June 14, 1988
October 11, 1988
October 18, 1988
November 22, 1988
Shire Album
30 Samplers
Sotheby's
Jan. 10, 1972 (2 copies)
May 18, 1979
October 31 & November 1, 1980
May 19, 1984
December 1, 1984
April/May 1985
May 30, 1987
Sotheby's, NY
June 9, 1978
April 10 & 11, 1981
Art books
American Folk Art: From the Abby Aldrich Rockefeller Folk Art Collection
Andrews, Faith and Edward Deming Andrews. Shaker Furniture: The Craftsmanship of an American Communal Sect
Bolton, Ethel Stanwood and Eva Johnston Coe. American Samplers
Burckhardt, Lucius. Werkbund Germania Austria Svizzera
Kreuger, Glee F. A Gallery of American Samplers: The Theodore H. Kapneck Collection
Stroong, Roy. Nicholas Hilliar
Art journals
Art East: A Review of Islamic and Asiatic Art
no. 1 (1982)
The Metropolitan Museum of Art Bulletin
(June 1970)
Pellizzi, Francesco. Adventures of the Symbol: Magic for the Sake of Art
Paper read at The Cooper Union, NY 1986.
Res
12 (Autumn 1986)
13 (Spring 1987)
14 (Autumn 1987)
Art exhibit catalogs
African Spirit Images and Identities
Amerikanische Zeichnungen 1930-1980. Menil Collection, Houston at: Städtische Galerie Frankfurt am Main November 28, 1985 - January 26, 1986
Catalog of Islamic Carpets at Oberlin
, vol. 36/1 (1978-79)
Cinquante ans de dessins américains 1930-1980.
Menil Collection, Houston at: Ecole nationale supérieure des Beaux-Arts, Paris
Delft 38e oude kunst -en antiekbeurs.
October 23 - November 4, 1986
Geknüpfte Bilder: Nomadenteppiche aus dem Orient
Howard Kanovitz: Arbeiten 1951-1978.
Akademie der Künste: September 2-October 21, 1979
Howard Kanovitz: Paintings, Pastels, Drawings 1951-1978.
Akademie der Künste: September 2-October 21, 1979
Kestner-Gesellschaft, Hanover: Dec. 7, 1979 - Jan. 27, 1980.
Pistoletto in Berlin.
Art auction catalog
Sotheby's.
Fine American Indian Art, April 21, 1979
Related Resources
Related Resources in the Music Library
C. F. Peters Collection of Morton Feldman Manuscripts, 1961-1969
Mus. Arc. 2.4
Collection of 79 works by Morton Feldman in either score or part formats (72 scores; 7 sets of parts). All but one item are ink manuscripts on vellum. These served as the masters that Feldman submitted to C. F. Peters and Peters published directly from these masters. Almost all of the manuscripts are in Morton Feldman's hand, except for two scores copied by John Cage and three items in the hand of a music copyist.
Morton Feldman Images by Jan Williams, 1974-1979
Mus. Arc. 2.3
A digitized collection of 56 images of Feldman and associates taken by percussionist Jan Williams during European concert tours in 1974, 1977, and 1979.
University at Buffalo Libraries Digital Collections
The University at Buffalo Libraries Digital Collections contain the digitized images of Feldman from other collections, including the Leo Smit Photograph Collection, Music Department Photograph Collection, Irene Haupt Photographs of Musicians in Buffalo, and the North American New Music Festival photographs.
Morton Feldman Lectures
List of seven lectures given by Feldman at the University at Buffalo. Transcriptions are available online for six of the lectures.
Related Online Resources
Paul Sacher Stiftung
The Paul Sacher Stiftung in Basel, Switzerland holds the principle collection of Morton Feldman materials. The online pages include contact information and a very basic outline of the collection contents.
Morton Feldman Page
Chris Villars's collection of information about Morton Feldman including Feldman's own texts, a bibliography, discography, list of works, etc.